Ting Pan

UX Engineer / Front End Developer

HCI student with passion and experience in design and development. Being enthusiastic about learning new stuff like VR, data analysis, and machine learning, I can quickly digest new knowledge, discovery new technology opportunities, and apply them in design and development process.

Education

Master of Science in Information Studies, The University of Texas at Austin		
• Graduate Research Assistant with Dr. Jakki Bailey in Virtual Reality Lab.		
Related courses: Algorithms, Introduction to Machine Learning, Information		
Retrieval, Advanced Design for Artificial Intelligence, Designing User Interfaces		
for Children.		
Bachelor of Architecture, China University of Mining and Technology		
 Study-abroad scholarship, awarded by China Scholarship Council. 		
 Outstanding student, and the 1st/2nd Prize Merit-Based Scholarship. 		
Exchange Student, University of Western Australia		
Completed comics project and sculpture installation.		

Experience

2019-01 - present	 Graduate Research Assistant in Virtual Reality Lab Taking charge of 3D modeling and animation. Developing VR game for children in Unity environment. Collecting and analyzing laboratory data in future work.
2019-01 - present	Volunteer Research Assistant in Image and Video Computing (IVC) Group • Involving in the development of accessible websites to support AI challenges.
2018-12 - 2019-03	 Volunteer in CHINA GATHERING @ SXSW Helped with media pitch, guest interview, and website development.
2016-04 - 2016-08	 Internship in Qian Cang Network Technology Co. Ltd Performed as a graphic designer that helps with website design and poster design for clients in a variety of industries.

Project

2018-12 -	Data Visualization Project for IEEE Pacific Visualization 2019 Competition
2019-03	 Analyzed food nutrition data; developed a website to present food story and data visualization; and built interactive functions using JavaScript.
2019-01 - 2019-02	 CHINA GATHERING @ SXSW Web Development Applied design strategy to improve user interface design and performed front-end web development as a lead developer.
2018-10 - 2018-11	 Spatial Exploration – AR Game for Children Education (Course Project) Designed the game content and interface independently; wrote a paper to scientifically explain design strategy.
2018-09 - 2018-11	 Austin Animal Adoption Website (Course Project) Used Python Flask to build the database and website framework; applied CNN model to extract animal feature.

Personal Info

Address

3600 N Hills Dr APT250 Austin, TX78731

Phone

+1 737 333 9769

E-mail

ting.pan@utexas.edu

Personal Website

http://tingpan.work

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ting-pan-546283155

GitHub

https://github.com/ CCCCChloe

Coding Skills

Python
Java
HTML5
CSS3
JavaScript
Library (Bootstrap, React.js, jQuery)
Swift
Processing

Design Skills

Design Thinking
Prototyping
Wireframing
Information Architecture
Data visualization

Software

Joithaic		
Unity	••••	
3ds Max	••••	
Rhinoceros	••••	
V-Ray	••••	
Photoshop	••••	
Illustrator	••••	
Premiere	••••	